Finding Aid for the Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo, 2003
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo,, 2003
Mus. Arc. 21
Haupt, Irene
1 box (61 photographs)
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Contains 61 photographs of musicians who participated in the June in Buffalo Festival 2003 at the University at Buffalo.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from Irene Haupt, 2004.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Alternate Forms
All images are available in the UB Libraries Digital Collections as part of the overall June in Buffalo Collection.
Biographical Note
Irene Haupt, a graduate of the State University of New York at Buffalo, has been documenting the Buffalo arts scene through her photography since 1976. During that time she has worked for, or with, some of the most notable institutions in Buffalo, including the Irish Classical Theatre, Studio Arena Theater, the Kavinoky Theatre, the Buffalo Philharmonic Orchestra, the Theatre of Youth, the Albright-Knox Art Gallery, and the State University of New York at Buffalo. In addition to her specialty of theater photography, Irene Haupt has also devoted much of her career to the photography of musicians and musical events. Most notable is her documentation of the contemporary music scene in Buffalo, including coverage of the University at Buffalo's June in Buffalo festival of new music, 1982-1987, and 2003 to the present. Over the course of those years, she has created a visual record that contains images of some of the most significant composers and performers of the last quarter century. The list of names is impressive: Aaron Copland, Morton Feldman, Leo Smit, Virgil Thomson, Steve Reich, Ralph Shapey, Henry Brant, Earle Brown, Ursula Oppens, Jan Williams, Lukas Foss, Philip Glass, Otto Luening, Conlon Nancarrow, Ernst Krenek, Larry Austin, Lejaren Hiller, Elliott Carter, Milton Babbitt, John Cage, Charles Wuorinen, Jacob Druckman, and Yvar Mikhashoff, among others.
The June in Buffalo festival of contemporary music was begun at the University at Buffalo in 1975 by composer Morton Feldman. He directed the festival 1975-1978 and in 1980. The festival was dormant from 1981 through 1985. David Felder revived the festival in 1986 and has been its director since that time.
Scope and Content Note
The collection of Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2003 contains 61 images of participants in the festival for 2003. The list of musicians includes Tony Conrad, David Felder, John Corigliano, Lukas Foss, Magnus Martnesson, Philip Glass, the New York New Music Ensemble, Steve Reich, Brad Lubman, and Charles Wuorinen
Arrangement
One sequence of images in alphabetical order by principal subject of the image.
Container List
- Photographs, June 2003, I.
  - Miles Anderson, trombone, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 01)
  - Tony Conrad, with violin and electronics, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 02)
  - Tony Conrad, with violin and electronics, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 03)
  - Tony Conrad, violin, with Jonathan Golove, electric violoncello, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 04)
  - John Corigliano, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 05)
  - John Corigliano, David Felder, and Bradley Lubman, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 06)
  - John Corigliano with the Quatuor Bozzini, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 07)
  - Anthony Cornicello at computer, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 08)
  - Anthony Cornicello and Chris Finckel, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 09)
  - David Felder at sound console, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 10)
  - David Felder standing at sound console, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 11)
  - David Felder standing at sound console, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 12)
  - David Felder gesturing with hand, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 13)
  - David Felder and Cheryl Gobbetti-Hoffman, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 14)
  - David Felder and Cheryl Gobbetti-Hoffman, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 15)
  - David Felder and Cheryl Gobbetti-Hoffman, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 16)
  - David Felder and Miles Anderson, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 17)
  - David Felder, Jayn Rosenfeld, Jean Kopperud, Linda Quan, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 18)
  - Christopher Finckel, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 19)
  - Lukas Foss at piano, June 2003, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 20)
  - Lukas Foss in overcoat, June 2003, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 21)
  - Lukas Foss in sportcoat, June 2003, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 22)
  - Lukas Foss in tuxedo, June 2003, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 23)
  - Lukas Foss with microphone, June 2003, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 24)
  - Lukas Foss with piano in background, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 25)
  - Lukas Foss and David Felder, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 26)
  - Lukas Foss and Magnus Martensson examining score, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 27)
  - Lukas Foss and Magnus Martensson at podium, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 28)
  - Lukas Foss and Edward Yadzinski, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 29)
  - Kevin Gallagher with guitar, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 30)
  - Kevin Gallagher, with guitar onstage, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 31)
  - Kevin Gallagher, with guitar onstage, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 32)
  - Philip Glass, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 33)
  - Philip Glass in front of microphone, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 34)
  - Philip Glass in jacket, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 35)
  - Philip Glass and David Felder, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 36)
  - Philip Glass and David Felder at piano, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 37)
  - Philip Glass taking bow onstage with Slee Sinfonietta and conductor, Magnus Martensson, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 38)
  - Cheryl Gobbetti-Hoffman and Susan Fancher, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 39)
  - Stephen Gosling at piano, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 40)
  - Stephen Gosling and Hila Plitmann, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 41)
  - Stephen Gosling and Marilyn Nonken, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 42)
  - Members of the New York New Music Ensemble, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 43)
  - Marilyn Nonken at piano, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 44)
  - Steve Reich, with Brad Lubman in background, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 45)
  - Steve Reich and Brad Lubman, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 46)
  - Steve Reich, Brad Lubman and violoncellist, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 47)
  - Steve Reich and Beryl Korot, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 48)
  - Steve Reich, Beryl Korot, and Jeff Stadelman, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 49)
  - Steve Reich and Brad Lubman examining score, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 50)
  - Charles Wuorinen, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 51)
  - Charles Wuorinen, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 52)
  - Charles Wuorinen, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 53)
  - Charles Wuorinen, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 54)
  - Charles Wuorinen, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 55)
  - Charles Wuorinen, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 56)
  - Charles Wuorinen, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 57)
  - Charles Wuorinen, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 58)
  - Charles Wuorinen, Magnus Martensson, and James Baker, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 59)
  - Charles Wuorinen at June in Buffalo 2003, June 2003, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 60)
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
June in Buffalo (Festival) (Buffalo, N.Y.)--Photographs; Composers--Photographs; Music festivals--New York (State)--Buffalo--Photographs; Musicians--Photographs
Genres
Photographs; Portraits
Associated Material
Related Resources
Related Resources in the Music Library
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2000
Mus. Arc. 18
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2000 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2001
Mus. Arc. 19
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2001 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2002
Mus. Arc. 21
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2002 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2004
Mus. Arc. 25
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2004 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2005
Mus. Arc. 27
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2005 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2006
Mus. Arc. 29
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2006 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2007
Mus. Arc. 38
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2007 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2008
Mus. Arc. 39
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2008 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2009
Mus. Arc. 50
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2009 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2010
Mus. Arc. 55
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2010 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2011
Mus. Arc. 56
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2011 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2012
Mus. Arc. 60
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2012 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2013
Mus. Arc. 66
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2013 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2014
Mus. Arc. 67
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2014 June in Buffalo.
June in Buffalo Photograph Collection
A selection of images from the June in Buffalo festivals is available through the University at Buffalo Libraries Digital Collections.